A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Administration and Officers Files, Office Files of Lonnie Sherrod FA1792
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Committee on Development, Giftedness, and the Learning Process, 1981-1986; 4; 3.31 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 3 legal document boxes
  - Funding, 1981-1985 (Box 30, Folder 215)
  - Materials for Mellon, 1984-1986 (Box 30, Folder 225, Box 31, Folder 226)
  - Letters to New Chair and Members, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 241)
  - MacArthur Foundation Planning, 1985-1986 (Box 33, Folder 255)
  - Workshop on Music and Knowledge - Jerusalem Conference Correspondence, 1985 June (Box 37, Folder 286, Box 38, Folder 287)
  - Mellon Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 40, Folder 301)
  - General Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 40, Folder 303-304)
  - Workshop on Development of Moral Action, 1984-1985 (Box 40, Folder 305)
  - Committee Meeting, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1984-1985 (Box 40, Folder 310, Box 41, Folder 311)
  - Giftedness - Committee on Giftedness Reappointment Letters, Moral Responsibility Materials, Minutes of 9/18, Summary Bibliography - Moral Responsibility Workshop, Gift Letters, Mellon, Bioletessa, Morresmin, Itemsmor, undated; 8" floppy disk (Box 64)
  - Mellon Progress Report - Gifted - Mellon Progress Report, Read - Training, undated; 8" floppy disk (Box 64)
- Inventory of Longitudinal Research on Childhood and Adolescence, 1975-1986; 5; 5.21 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes and 3 legal document boxes
  In 1984, the Social Science Research Council's Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective, a subcommittee of the Committee on Life-Course Perspectives on Human Development published an Inventory of Longitudinal Research on Childhood and Adolescence compiled by Frederick Verdonik and Lonnie Sherrod. The inventory summarizes 116 studies. The summaries include the title of the study, names and affiliations of the investigators, disciplines covered, years of completed waves, instruments used for data collection, future plans for the study, references, and indicated whether the study is active and available for further study. This inventory followed a previous inventory called An Inventory of Longitudinal Studies of Middle and Old Age compiled by Susan Migdal, Robald B. Abeles, and Lonnie Sherrod that was published by the Committee on Life-Course Perspectives on Human Development in 1981.
  In 1986, the Committee coordinated with the Henry A. Murray Research Center of Radcliffe College to continue developing the inventory and archiving more recent studies. In 1991, the Council published a revised volume titled Inventory of Longitudinal Studies in the Social Sciences, edited by Copeland H. Young, Kristen L. Savola, and Erin Phelps. Funding for the project was provided by a grant from the National Institute of Mental Health to Radcliffe College.
  The series consists of working documents related to the Inventory of Longitudinal Research on Childhood and Adolescence, an SSRC publication compiled by Frederick Verdonik and Lonnie Sherrod. The series contains forms filled out by study investigators, inventory summaries, correspondence, and drafts.
  - An Inventory of Longitudinal Research on Childhood and Adolescence, Frederick Verdonik and Lonnie Sherrod - Working Documents, 1977-1984 (Box 26, Folder 181, Box 27, Folder 182)
  - Semantic Memory: A Free-Elements System, Stéphane Ehrlich, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 183)
  - History of the SSRC in Child Development, Lonnie Sherrod, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 184)
  - Finding Time: The Subjective Dates of Natural Events in Very Long Term Memory, Norman K. Brown, Steven K. Shevell, and Lance J. Rips - Draft, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 185)
  - Summaries of Studies A-Z, undated (Box 27, Folder 186)
  - Longitudinal Study of Twins, Dr. Gottschaldt, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 187)
  - Articles, 1975-1984 (Box 27, Folder 188)
  - Inventory List To Be Sent Out for Comments and Recommendations, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 189)
  - Disk Summaries, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 190)
  - Meeting of Subcommittee on Vol. I of the Inventory of Longitudinal Research on Childhood and Adolescence, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 191)
  - File Status Forms, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 192)
  - Summary Forms, undated (Box 28, Folder 193)
  - Background, undated (Box 28, Folder 194)
  - Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective, Inventory of Longitudal Research on Childhood - Letter of Intro About the Subcommittee (First Mailing Info), undated (Box 28, Folder 195)
  - Instruments Used/Constructs Measured Forms, undated (Box 28, Folder 196)
  - Age Range Per Age Group/Sex Distribution, undated (Box 28, Folder 197)
  - Suggested Studies Forms, undated (Box 28, Folder 198)
  - Information Summary Forms: Ages, undated (Box 28, Folder 199)
  - Subcommitte on Child and Adolescent Development: Inventory Information (Originals), undated (Box 28, Folder 200)
  - Lists of Mailings to Principal Investigators, 1981-1982 (Box 28, Folder 201)
  - Inventory Summaries, undated (Box 28, Folder 202-203)
  - African Gnosis: Philosophy and the Order of Knowledge by V. Y. Mudimbe, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 204)
  - World Data Set, Thomas Jordon, undated (Box 28, Folder 205)
  - Glueck's Prospective Study of Delinquency, G. Valliant, 1979-1982 (Box 28, Folder 206)
  - Responses to Requests, 1984-1985 (Box 29, Folder 207-210)
  - Bibliography Notecards, undated (Box 29, Folder 211-212)
  - Inventory Correspondence, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 263)
  - Verdonik and Sherrod - Inventory Requests, 1984-1986 (Box 35, Folder 269)
  - Verdonik and Sherrod - Inventory Requests - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 35, Folder 270-272)
  - An Inventory of Longitudinal Research on Childhood and Adolescence - Proofs, 1985 April (Box 37, Folder 280-282)
  - Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective - Longitudinal Research - Compendium of Findings, 1983-1984 (Box 40, Folder 306)
  - Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective - Inventory on Longitudinal Child Development Research - Study Summaries, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 355-356)
  - Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective Meeting January 1984 - Inventory on Longitudinal Child Development Research - Findings, 1983-1984 (Box 48, Folder 357)
  - Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective - Inventory on Longitudinal Child Development February 1984 Meeting (Box 48, Folder 358)
  - An Inventory of Longitudinal Research on Childhood and Adolescence - Thanks, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 359)
  - Status Updates and Correspondence, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 360)
  - Inventory on Longitudinal Child Development - Introductory Material - Letters, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 363)
  - Drafts with Edits, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 387-390, Box 54, Folder 391)
  - Preparation of Inventory Volume I, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 392)
  - Correspondence, Error Letters, 1985-1986 (Box 60, Folder 415)
- Committee on Biosocial Perspectives on Parent Behavior, 1981-1986; 6; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  The Social Science Research Council's Committee on Biosocial Perspectives on Parent Behavior was active from 1980-1991. The Committee built upon the SSRC's previous work in the fields of human behavior and biology in the Committee on Biological Bases of Social Behavior (1966-1979) and the Committee on Biosocial Science (1976-1980). The committee consisted of biological, behavioral, and social scientists with the goals of exploring the interplay between biological and social phenomena and advancing understanding of human behavior. The Committee received funding from the William T. Grant Foundation.
  The series contains correspondence, grant reports, conference files, and meeting materials.
  - Letters to New Chair and Members, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 240)
  - Conference on School-Age Pregnancies and Parenthood, May 24-26, 1982, 1982-1983 (Box 59, Folder 403)
  - Conference on School-Age Pregnancies and Parenthood, May 24-26, 1982 - Background Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 59, Folder 404)
  - Papers and Local Arrangements, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 405)
  - May 20-23 Business Meeting and Materials for Child Abuse Meeting, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 406)
  - General, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 407)
  - William T. Grant Foundation Progress Report: Year One, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 408)
  - William T. Grant Foundation Funding for Biosocial Science, 1981-1982 (Box 59, Folder 409)
  - William T. Grant Foundation Progress Report: Year Two, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 410)
  - School Age Pregnancy Book Correspondence, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 411)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 412)
- Administrative Files, 1982-1987; 7; 4.93 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes, 2 legal document boxes, 1 half-letter box
  This series consists of administrative files related to Lonnie Sherrod's obligations to the Social Science Research Council and the committees on which he served as a staff liaison. The series contains correspondence, notes, drafts of annual reports, and material related to his role as Treasurer for the Society for the Study of Social Biology (SSSB) from 1984-1990.
  - Lonnie R. Sherrod Business Cards, undated (Box 26, Folder 180)
  - Provisional Contents of Items (SSRC Publication), 1985-1986 (Box 31, Folder 227)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) - Drafts of Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 31, Folder 228)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) - Adolescence Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 31, Folder 229)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy (P&P) - Exciting Ideas for Projects Discussion, 1985-1987 (Box 31, Folder 230)
  - Annual Report Statement Drafts for SSRC Committees, Biosocial Perspectives on Parent Behavior and Offspring Development, Development, Giftedness, and the Learning Process and Life-Course Perspectives on Human Development, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 235)
  - Memos Regarding Contents of December Items, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 236)
  - New Member Information Sheets for SSRC Committees, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 237-238)
  - Chronological Files - Mintauri Preston, Program Assistant and Lonnie Sherrod, Staff Associate, 1986-1987 (Box 34, Folder 267, Box 35, Folder 268)
  - Copy of D-Base, undated; 5.25" floppy disk (Box 36)
  - Untitled Floppy Disk, undated; 5.25" floppy disk (Box 36)
  - Untitled Floppy Disk, undated; 5.25" floppy disk (Box 36)
  - IBM Guides, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 279)
  - Disk 1 As Converted, undated; 5.25" floppy disk (Box 36)
  - Disk 2 Page Numbers Converted to Sequential, undated; 5.25" floppy disk (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 288)
  - Reappointment Letters, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 289-290)
  - Chron File, 1985 May-September (Box 39, Folder 298)
  - Student Recommendation Letters, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 402)
  - Chron File, 1984 November-1985 January (Box 41, Folder 312-314)
  - General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 315)
  - General Correspondence, 1985 February-March (Box 41, Folder 316)
  - 1985 Annual Report Correspondence - Summaries of Committees' Programs (Box 42, Folder 317)
  - SSSB - Lonnie CV, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Secadmia (?), Giftedness, Committee Workshop, Gadnes (?) Paper, Items, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Untitled, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - MR CCP (?) Prop., Brain and Behavior Conference, Precursors of Adolescence, Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective Paper, Giftedness Workshop Memo, Society for the Study of Social Biology, Wehnert Letter, Jane Carey Letter, Society for the Study of Social Biology, undated (Box 42)
  - Berlin Volume, King Letter, Mellon Foundation, Expertise Can Th You (?), Shilansky (?) Reference Letter, Moral Action, Proposal, Pres-Cumo of Ad Conf, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Index and Invent, Sherrod Article, BSS Brain and Behavior Conference Info, Burn Letter, Pearson Letters, SR CD History Panel, SSSB Tape 2, Boyd Letter, SSSB Minutes, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - T 85 len.(?), undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - La Rose Letter - W Sedaie - Cent Meeting Minutes, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Last Minute Arrang for Israel, Selfhood, Business Meeting Bin-Joe, PP Minutes, Israel Thank You, Inventory Info, 1985 June; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Biosocial Transfer of Rights, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - SSSB #2, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Terry, SSSB Letter, Renewed (?) Test (Members), undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Volkswagen, undated; 8-inch floppy disk (Box 42)
  - Society for the Study of Social Biology (SSSB) Did Not Renew in 1983-1984 (Box 42, Folder 320-321)
  - Society for the Study of Social Biology (SSSB) - Renewed through 1983 (Box 42, Folder 322)
  - Society for the Study of Social Biology (SSSB) - Not on Existing Membership Roster, undated (Box 42, Folder 323)
  - Social Biology, Volume 29, Number 3-4, Fall-Winter, Published by the Society for the Study of Social Biology (SSSB), 1982 (Box 42, Folder 324, Box 43, Folder 325)
  - The Population Council Staff Directory, 1985 March (Box 43, Folder 326)
  - Society for the Study of Social Biology (SSSB) - Renewed Through 1984 (Box 43, Folder 327)
  - Society for the Study of Social Biology (SSSB) - Renewed in 1984 but not in 1983 (Box 43, Folder 328)
  - Mishkenot Conference (Israel), Giftedness Committee Contents: Invitation Letter, Matrix - Name and Address List, 1984-1985; 8" floppy disk (Box 64)
- Publications, 1964-1987; 8; 9.89 Cubic Feet 28 containers
  This series consists of books, journals, and newsletters that Lonnie Sherrod received in the course of his work with the Social Science Research Council.
  - Psychological Abstracts, American Psychological Association Volumes 69-74, 1983-1987 (Box 11, Folder 86-89, Box 12, Folder 90-94, Box 13, Folder 95-98, Box 14, Folder 99-104, Box 15, Folder 105-108, Box 16, Folder 109-113, Box 17, Folder 114-118, Box 18, Folder 119-122, Box 19, Folder 123-127)
    Box 11:
    Volume 69 No. 2, February 1983
    Volume 69, Number 3, March 1983
    Volume 69, Number 4, April 1983
    Volume 69, No. 6, Part 2, Index, January-June 1983
    Box 12:
    Volume 70, Number 1, July 1983
    Volume 70, Number 2, August 1983
    Volume 70, Number 3, September 1983
    Volume 70, Number 5, November 1983
    Volume 70, Number 6, Part 1, December 1983
    Box 13:
    Volume 70, Number 6, Part 2 Index, July-December 1983
    Volume 71, Number 1, January 1984
    Volume 71, Number 2, February 1984
    Volume 71, Number 3, March 1984
    Box 14
    Volume 71, Number 4, April 1984
    Volume 71, Number 5, May 1984
    Volume 71, Number 6, June 1984
    Volume 71, Number 7, July 1984
    Volume 71, Number 8, August 1984
    Volume 71, Number 9, September 1984
    Box 15:
    Volume 71, Number 10, October 1984
    Volume 71, Number 11, November 1984
    Volume 71, Number 12, December 1984
    Volume 71, Author Index, January-December 1984
    Box 16:
    Volume 71, Subject Index II, January-December 1984
    Volume 72, Number 1, January 1985
    Volume 72, Number 3, March 1985
    Volume 72, Number 3, April 1985
    Volume 72, Number 5, May 1985
    Box 17:
    Volume 72, Number 6, June 1985
    Volume 72, Number 9, September 1985
    Volume 72, Number 10, April 1985
    Volume 72, Number 12, December 1985
    Volume 72, Author Index, January-December 1985
    Box 18:
    Volume 72, Subject Index II, January-December 1985
    Volume 73, Number 1, January 1986
    Volume 73, Number 3, March 1986
    Volume 73, Number 4, April 1986
    Volume 73, Number 5, May 1986
    Box 19:
    Volume 73, Number 6, June 1986
    Volume 73 No. 9, September 1986
    Volume 74, Number 1, January 1987
    Volume 74, Number 4, April 1987
  - The Sense of Well-Being in America: Recent Patterns and Trends, Angus Campbell, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 128)
  - Methodology in Evaluation of Psychiatric Treatment, Edited by T. Helgason, European Science Foundation, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 129)
  - Early and Middle Adulthood, Lillian E. Troll, Life-Span Development Series, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 130)
  - World Health Organization Publications - Catalogue Supplement, 1974-1979, Supplement, 1980-1984, Second Edition (Box 20, Folder 131)
  - Aging from Birth to Death, Interdisciplinary Perspectives, Edited by Matilda White Riley, American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 132)
  - Life Course Dynamics: Trajectories and Transitions, 1968-1980, Edited by Glen H. Elder, Jr., 1985 (Box 20, Folder 133)
  - International Society for the Study of Behavioral Development, Seventh Biennial Meeting, Munich, W. Germany, 1983 July 31-August 4 (Box 21, Folder 134)
  - Zero to Three: Bulletin of the National Center for Clinical Infant Programs, 1983-1985 (Box 21, Folder 135)
  - World Health Organization Publications Catalogue 1947-1979, Supplement 1980-1983 (Box 21, Folder 137)
  - Youth in Transition, Volume I: Blueprint for a Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Boys, Institute for Social Research, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 138)
  - 1982 Directory, Society for Research in Child Development (Box 21, Folder 139)
  - A Guide to Resources and Services, 1975-1976, Inter-University Consortium for Political Research, Institute for Social Research (Box 21, Folder 140)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science Handbook Officers Organization Activities, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 141)
  - Data Available, Inter-University Consortium for Political Research, Institute for Social Research, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 142)
  - Guide to Resources and Services, Inter-University Consortium for Political Research, Institute for Social Research, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 143)
  - Social Stress, Edited by Sol Levine and Norman A. Scotch, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 144)
  - International Society for the Study of Behavioral Development, Seventh Biannual Meetings, Abstracts, Poster Presentations, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 145)
  - Preventing the Harmful Consequences of Severe and Persistent Loneliness, National Institute of Mental Health, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 146)
  - Newsletters, 1982-1986 (Box 22, Folder 147)
  - East-West Center Publications Lists, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 148)
  - On the Dynamics Between Growth and Decline in the Aging of Intelligence and Memory, Paul B. Baltes and Reinhold Kliegl, Max Planck Institute for Human Development and Education, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 149)
  - Expertise in Life Planning: A New Research Approach to Investigating Aspects of Wisdom, Jacqui Smith, Roger A. Dixon, and Paul B. Baltes, Max Planck Institute for Human Development and Education, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 150)
  - Developmental Psychology Newsletter, Division 7, American Psychological Association, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 151)
  - Seminar College, New School for Social Research Bulletin, Volume 42, Number 3, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 152)
  - American Psychologist, Volume 41, Number 9, 1986 September (Box 23, Folder 153)
  - Foundation for Child Development Annual Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 23, Folder 154)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York Annual Report, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 155)
  - Annual Report, Institute of Child Development, University of Minnesota, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 156)
  - Annals of The New York Academy of Sciences, Volume 449, Annals Index, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 157)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Science, Volume 231, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 158)
  - American Psychological Association 89th Convention, Los Angeles, 1981 August (Box 23, Folder 159)
  - Foundation and Organization Newsletters and Reports, 1979-1987 (Box 24, Folder 160)
  - The Henry A. Murray Research Center of Radcliffe College: A Center for the Study of Lives - A Guide to the Data Resources, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 161)
  - The Henry A. Murray Research Center of Radcliffe College: A Center for the Study of Lives - Annual Report, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 162)
  - 1974 Directory - Society for Research in Child Development (Box 24, Folder 163)
  - Inventory of the New York Longitudinal Study, Prepared by Jacqueline V. Lerner and Richard M. Lerner, Pennsylvania State University, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 164)
  - Project Metropolitan: A Longitudinal Study of a Stockholm Cohort, Research Reports 5,19, and 21, 1976-1984 (Box 24, Folder 165)
  - Merrill Palmer Quarterly, Behavior and Development, 1977-1981 (Box 24, Folder 166)
  - Society for Research in Child Development Newsletters, 1979-1986 (Box 25, Folder 167)
  - Child Health and Human Development: An Overview and Strategy for a Five-Year Research Plan, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 168)
  - The Older Person's Handbook: Ideas, Projects, and Resources for Neighborhood Action by Michael Cala with Susan Lob and Marian Sroge, A Mutual Aid Project Handbook, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 169)
  - Man and Beast: Revisited, Special Smithsonian Symposium, 1986 May 6-8 (Box 25, Folder 170)
  - American Psychologist - Volume 40, Number 12 and Volume 41, Numbers 4 and 6, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 171)
  - Deterring the Effects of Aging on the Central Nervous System, Free University of Berlin, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 172)
  - American Psychological Association - 87th Annual Convention, 1979 September 1-5 (Box 26, Folder 173)
  - Science (Computer Issue), American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 174)
  - Stress, Success, and Survival, Harvard Publication, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 175)
  - Publication Manual Change Sheets, APA, 1975; 1977 (Box 26, Folder 176)
  - Newsletters and Reports, 1983-1986 (Box 26, Folder 177-178)
    Folder 177:
    About Russell Sage Foundation, undated
    Zero to Three, Bulletin of the National Center for Clinical Infant Programs, Vol. VI. No. 2, December 1985
    Population and Family Planning Programs, A Compendium of Data Through 1983, Dorothy L. Nortman
    1984 Catalog, Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Inc. Publishers
    Folder 178:
    NIH Data Book, 1984
    Social Welfare Research Center (SWRC) Reports and Proceedings, No. 59, May 1986 - Community Care of the Aged, Ruth Errey, Carole Baker, and Sarah Fox
    Social Welfare Research Center (SWRC) Newsletter, No. 21, May 1986
    SSRC Annual Report Reprint - A Life-Course Perspective on the Later Years of Life: Some Implications for Research, Ronald P. Abeles and Matilda White Riley
    Research Programs of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, US Department of Health and Human Services,
  - Computer Directory Structure, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 179)
  - Five Thousand American Families - Patterns of Economic Progress, Volumes I, II, III, VIII, 1975-1980 (Box 35, Folder 274, Box 36, Folder 275-277)
  - The Seven Ages of Man: A Survey of Human Development - Body, Personality, Ability - Through Life, Robert R. Sears and S. Shirley Feldman, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 278)
  - Transitions: The Family and the Life Course in Historical Perspective, Edited by Tamara K. Harevan, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 393)
  - The Identification of Progress in Learning, Edited by T. Hägerstrand, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 394)
  - Health Indicators, Edited by A.J. Culver, 1983 (Box 54, Folder 395)
  - Longitudinal Studies of Adult Psychological Development, Edited by K. Warner Schaie, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 396)
  - Adulthood and Aging: An Interdisciplinary, Developmental View, Douglas C. Kimmel, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 397)
  - Mid-Career Development: Research Perspectives on a Development Community for Senior Administrators, Robert N. Rapoport, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 398)
  - Aging in Society: Selected Reviews of Recent Research, Edited by Matilda White Riley, Beth B. Hess, and Kathleen Bond, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 399)
  - Handbook of Aging and the Social Sciences, Edited by Robert H. Binstock and Ethel Shanas, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 400)
  - Social Biology Volume 31, 1-4 Spring-Winter Index, Contents (Microfilm shipped to Dr. Sherrod at SSRC), 1984 (Box 57)